Guide to the Stanford Emeriti Council Collection SC0973
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Emeriti Council collection
2006-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Emeriti Council
SC0973
1 Linear Feet
Collection pertains to talks sponsored by the Council and includes DVDs, digital videocassettes, and miscellaneous printed materials. Speakers represented in the collection include Luigi Cavalli-Sforza, Herant Katchadourian, Herbert Lindenberger, Albert Macovski, and Eleanor Maccoby.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to talks sponsored by the Council and includes DVDs, digital videocassettes, and miscellaneous printed materials. Speakers represented in the collection include Luigi Cavalli-Sforza, Herant Katchadourian, Herbert Lindenberger, Albert Macovski, and Eleanor Maccoby.
Universities and colleges -- Faculty.; Stanford University -- Faculty.; Katchadourian, Herant A.; Shah, Haresh C.; Macovski, Albert; March, James G.; Maccoby, Eleanor E.; Cavalli-Sforza, L. L. (Luigi Luca); Stanford Emeriti Council; Lindenberger, Herbert
- Announcements, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Audiovisual recordings, 2006-2011
  - Bienenstock, Arthur, 2011-11-07; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Cavalli-Sforza, L. L. (Luigi Luca), 1922-, 2008-04-23; 1.1; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.1U)
  - Katchadourian, Herant A., 2009-02-23; 1.2; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.2U)
  - Kornberg, Arthur, 1918-2007, 2007-05-14; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Lindenberger, Herbert, 1929-, 2009-11-10; 1.3; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.3U)
  - Maccoby, Eleanor E., 1917-, 2008-10-21; 1.6; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.6U)
  - Macovski, Albert, 1929-, 2009-05-26; 1.4; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.4U1)
    - Audio, 2009 May 26; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1.4U2)
  - March, James G., 2010-02-02; 1.8; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.8U)
  - Middlebrook, Diane Wood, 1939-2007, 2007-01-23; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Panel on Health Care in the U.S.: A Work in Progress, 2010-04-14; 1.10; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1.10U)
    Scope and Contents
    Panelists: Enthoven, Alain; Fuchs, Victor; Garber, Alan; Milstein, Arnold. Co-sponsored by the Emeriti Council and the Stanford Historical Society, this panel discussion of problems and prospects of our country's health care system addresses an obviously important and timely topic. Among the topics the panel considered are the strengths and weaknesses of Congressional legislation; tradeoffs involving coverage, cost,a nd quality of care; how to limit the spiraling costs of health care; the political feasibility of various proposals for health care reform; and what the private sector and individuals can do regardless of what happens in Washington.
    Pizzo, Philip A.; Fuchs, Victor R.; Enthoven, Alain C.; Milstein, Arnold; Garber, Alan M.
  - Shah, Haresh C., "Expect the unexpected: Catastrophe Risk Management", 2010-06-09; 1.9; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.9U)
  - Suppes, Patrick, 1922-2014, 2006-05-23; 2 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - "Zach", 2009-04-23; 1.5; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1.5U)
- Audiovisual recordings, 2007-2016, Accession ARCH-2016-124
  - Autobiographical reflections: Alain Enthoven, 2016-03-15; 1.01; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections Saul A. Rosenberg, 2014-02-20; 1.02; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council meeting James -03- autobiographical, undated; 1.03; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Herbert Lindenberger, 2009-11-10; 1.04; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
  - Middlebrook Emeriti Council lecture, 2007-01-23; 1.05; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections Walter Vicenti, 2015-01-28; 1.06; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Faculty Development and Diversity, 2013-03-21; 1.07; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Faculty Development and Diversity, 2013-03-21; 1.08; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Professor Bandura mp3, 2015-12-01; 1.09; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections: Donald Knuth, 2016-04-25; 1.10; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Middlebrook Emeriti Council lecture, 2007-01-23; 1.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Lecture Artie Bienenstock, 2011-11-07; 1.12; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections Thomas Ehrlich, 2013-11-19; 1.13; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections: Helen Quinn, 2014-12-09; 1.14; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Lecture Paul Brest, 2011-02-07; 1.15; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical Reflections: Saul Rosenberg, 2014-02-20; 1.16; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections John Chowning, 2012-04-30; 1.17; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections John Chowning, 2012-04-30; 1.18; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical Reflections William F. Miller, 2013-05-30; 1.19; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Arthur Kornberg Talk, 2007-05-14; 1.20; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiography - Haresh Shah, 2010-06; 1.21; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections "Expect the Unexpected: Catastrophe Risk Management" Haresh Shah, 2010-06-09; 1.22; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Lecture Herant Katchadourian, 2009-02-23; 1.23; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Lecture Nancy Packer, 2012-11-12; 1.24; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Lecture David M. Kennedy, 2010-11-15; 1.25; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Meeting Autobiographical Reflections James -03-, 2010-02-02; 1.26; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Meeting tape 2 of 2 James -03-, 2010-02-02; 1.27; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council meeting Emeriti Council Meeting James -03-, 2010-02-02; 1.28; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections Thomas Ehrlich, 2013-11-19; 1.29; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Herbert Lindenberger Emeriti Council, 2009-11-10; 1.30; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council, Eleanor Maccoby, 2008-10-21; 1.31; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Eleanor MCCOBY, 2008-10-21; 1.32; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections: Michael Kirst, 2014-06-09; 1.33; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Albert Macovski, 2009-05-26; 1.34; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections: Wanda Corn, 2011-04-26; 1.35; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - autobiographical reflections: Wanda Corn disk 2 of 2, 2011-04-26; 1.36; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical Reflections William F. Miller, 2013-05-30; 1.37; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Autobiographical reflections Walter Vicenti, 2015-01-28; 1.38; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)
  - Emeriti Council Lecture Sandy Dornbusch, 2012-03-07; 1.39; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 1)